So we know what a routine is now.
所以我们现在知道什么是例行公事了。
We need to know how to introduce it.
我们需要知道如何介绍它。
OK so let's talk about how we can do that to start we need to say when things happen.
好的，让我们谈谈我们如何才能开始，我们需要在事情发生时说。
So very simple here we can just say and we often use the present tense by the way because these are
在这里非常简单，我们可以说，顺便说一下，我们经常使用现在时，因为这些是
things that didn't only happen before because it's part of your routine.
以前不会发生的事情，因为它是你日常生活的一部分。
It's stuff that you do often.
这是你经常做的事情。
Right.
正确的。
So we can use the present tense which makes it a lot easier to describe your routine because when you're
所以我们可以使用现在时，这样更容易描述你的日常生活，因为当你
doing it in the past it can be difficult to remember the past tense.
在过去这样做可能很难记住过去时。
Right.
正确的。
So we can just use the present tense.
所以我们可以只用现在时。
You don't need to use will either.
你也不需要使用 will。
Just use the present tense.
只需使用现在时。
What we often use words of frequency words a frequency like usually sometimes often regularly.
我们经常使用的频率词的频率通常有时经常经常。
I think you probably know most of these words.
我想你可能知道大部分这些词。
So let's let's start with time OK.
那么让我们从时间开始吧。
At 10:00 at 10:00 at 10:00 that's probably going to be 10:00 a.m. If you don't say p.m. or am and the
在 10:00 到 10:00 到 10:00，那可能是上午 10:00。如果你不说 p.m.或者我和
situation makes it pretty clear that you're talking about either morning or evening.
这种情况很清楚地表明你在谈论早上或晚上。
It's OK to leave that out.
可以忽略它。
I could say I usually go to bed around 10:00 so that's going to be P.M. I usually get up around 10:00
我可以说我通常在 10:00 左右上床睡觉，所以那将是 P.M.我通常在 10:00 左右起床
or go to work around 10:00 probably that's going to be a.m. And if it's not then you will say I have
或者在 10:00 左右上班
a very weird job where I go to work at 10:00 p.m. at night.
一个非常奇怪的工作，我晚上 10:00 去上班。晚上。
Right.
正确的。
You'll say that you'll say p.m. if it's different.
你会说你会说 p.m.如果它不同。
But otherwise we can often leave that out.
但除此之外，我们通常可以忽略它。
OK.
好的。
So at 10:00 I usually I usually have a snack and then within that usually maybe there's a sometimes
所以在 10:00，我通常会吃点零食，然后通常可能会有
you could say sometimes I have sometimes sometimes I have cookie as a treat.
你可以说有时我有时有时我有饼干作为一种享受。
You could say but more often more often I have some fruit but a cup of fruit if you have a very good
你可以说，但更多时候我有一些水果，但如果你有一个非常好的水果杯
diet.
饮食。
Good eating habits.
良好的饮食习惯。
All right.
好的。
We can use sometimes even though it's inside usually.
我们有时可以使用，即使它通常在里面。
Usually you have the snack but when you have this snack sometimes it's a cookie.
通常你有零食，但当你有这种零食时，有时它是饼干。
More often it's fruit.
更多的时候是水果。
If you're a healthy healthy person don't eat too many cookies you'll get fat.
如果你是一个健康的人，不要吃太多饼干，你会发胖。
They'll want to do that.
他们会想要这样做。
That is no good.
那不好。
OK.
好的。
We could also say when we do things in order to help keep things in order.
我们也可以说我们什么时候做事是为了帮助保持秩序。
Right.
正确的。
A routine is usually this followed by this followed by this this this this this this this this we don't
例程通常是 this 后跟 this 后跟 this this this this this this this this 我们没有
always want to use the time because that can start to feel repetitive can start to feel like it's repeating
总是想利用时间，因为那会开始感觉重复 开始感觉像是在重复
too much.
太多了。
We can instead use after that after that after that.
在那之后，我们可以在之后使用。
So you could say for example after that I often I often check you check my email or I often respond
所以你可以说，例如，在那之后我经常检查你检查我的电子邮件或者我经常回复
to some emails that would be a pretty typical thing to do after a snack.
一些电子邮件，这将是一个非常典型的零食后做的事情。
You don't need to say after my snack because we just said that we had a snack.
你不需要在吃完我的零食后说，因为我们只是说我们吃了零食。
I have a snack.
我有一个小吃。
Usually at 10 after that after the snack is over I usually check my emails.
通常在零食结束后的 10 点，我通常会查看我的电子邮件。
And then you can say maybe where you check them if you want to mention where it happens you could say
然后你可以说也许你在哪里检查它们如果你想提到它发生的地方你可以说
at that my my desk.
那是我的办公桌。
But you don't have to say at my desk because that might be maybe obvious.
但是您不必在我的办公桌前说，因为这可能很明显。
Maybe it's kind of obvious that you check e-mails at your desk so you can add details or not.
也许很明显，您在办公桌上查看电子邮件以便您可以添加或不添加详细信息。
Sometimes in the routine there's something that happens if this happens but maybe this doesn't happen.
有时在例行程序中，如果发生这种情况会发生一些事情，但也许这不会发生。
So then we can introduce it like this if if I don't take the bus if I don't take the bus I usually remember
那么那么我们可以这样介绍 如果我不坐公共汽车 如果我不坐公共汽车 我通常记得
the pronunciation of usually is you use.
通常是你使用的发音。
Usually I usually walk.
通常我会走路。
So instead of driving.
所以，而不是开车。
Right.
正确的。
This kind of suggests that you do usually take the bus but there are times when you don't and when you
这种建议您通常会乘坐公共汽车，但有时您不乘坐公共汽车，有时您
don't you usually walk don't let that confuse you.
你不经常走路不要让那迷惑你。
Just because I say I usually walk.
只是因为我说我通常走路。
That doesn't mean I usually walk.
这并不意味着我通常走路。
I usually walk when I don't take the bus so maybe I take the bus this often like 90 percent of the time.
当我不坐公共汽车时，我通常会走路，所以我可能有 90% 的时间经常坐公共汽车。
This is the bus.
这是公共汽车。
But maybe maybe these are the times when I missed the bus.
但也许这些是我错过公共汽车的时候。
Right.
正确的。
The bus left.
公共汽车离开了。
I missed it.
我错过了。
And so what do I do in these times.
那么在这些时候我该怎么办。
Now forget about the first usually forget about how often that happens.
现在忘记第一次通常忘记这种情况发生的频率。
Now we're only talking about this period of time.
现在我们只谈论这段时间。
I usually walk or I usually drive my car or I usually take a taxi so that's OK to do.
我通常步行，或者我通常开车，或者我通常乘坐出租车，所以可以这样做。
In fact that's a very common thing to do.
事实上，这是一件很常见的事情。
But to be clear sometimes our actions depend on whether or not things happen that are completely out
但要明确的是，有时我们的行动取决于是否发生了完全不存在的事情
of our control if if it rains.
如果下雨，我们可以控制。
OK.
好的。
So what do you do when it rains.
那么下雨天怎么办。
If it rains I take a taxi and you can do this for everything.
如果下雨，我会坐出租车，你可以做任何事情。
When you're describing what you're doing usually or on a regular basis on a regular on a regular basis
当您描述您通常或定期在做的事情时
then you can use this basic structure.
那么你可以使用这个基本结构。
If this I do this and it can be a choice that you make if I.
如果这样做，我会这样做，如果我这样做，您可以做出选择。
And then what happens after that.
然后在那之后会发生什么。
Or it could be something out of your control something that just happens if it rains.
或者它可能是你无法控制的事情，如果下雨就会发生。
There are times when maybe if isn't the best phrase to use because we want to focus on the fact that
有时候，如果不是最好的短语，因为我们想专注于这样一个事实
every single time this happens I do this or we do this.
每次发生这种情况时，我都会这样做或我们这样做。
So there we can use whenever whenever focus is on every time before we said if it rains right.
因此，在我们说是否下雨之前，我们可以在每次关注时使用。
Maybe I do this maybe I do this whenever means every time whenever my boss is out of the office maybe
也许我会这样做 也许我会在任何时候这样做，每次我的老板不在办公室时
he's on a business trip right.
他是出差吧。
Whenever my boss is out of the office everyone in my department wants something silly brings beer to
每当我的老板不在办公室时，我部门的每个人都想要一些愚蠢的东西，带来啤酒
work brings beer brings beer whatever you want to say.
工作带来啤酒带来啤酒，无论你想说什么。
But the point is that it happens every time this happens.
但关键是每次发生这种情况时都会发生这种情况。
That doesn't mean your boss is always gone every time your boss is gone.
这并不意味着每次你的老板离开时你的老板都会离开。
You bring beer to the office.
你把啤酒带到办公室。
One of the things that's part of a normal professional day.
这是正常职业日的一部分。
If you're a student then maybe you would just say lunch or sometimes your lunch period right.
如果您是学生，那么也许您只会说午餐或有时您的午餐时间。
Lunch is the time when you eat lunch right.
午餐是您正确吃午餐的时间。
Or if you're at an office worker or you have a job where you need to have or keep regular hours.
或者，如果您在办公室工作，或者您有一份需要或保持正常工作时间的工作。
You might say my lunch break.
你可能会说我的午休时间。
This is the special time during the day when you can stop working and take lunch or eat lunch.
这是一天中的特殊时间，您可以停止工作并吃午餐或吃午餐。
It doesn't mean that you actually eat something although probably you do.
这并不意味着你真的吃了一些东西，尽管你可能会吃。
The point is it's this specific time set aside for you to do that.
关键是，这是为您预留的特定时间。
So maybe you have a one hour lunch break or a 30 minute lunch break.
所以也许你有一个 1 小时的午休时间或 30 分钟的午休时间。
I'm on my lunch break.
我正在午休。
People will say I'm on my lunch break.
人们会说我在午休。
Hey look can you could you please talk to this client.
嘿，看你能不能和这个客户谈谈。
We're you know we really need.
我们是你知道我们真的需要。
We really need your help.
我们真的需要你的帮助。
Oh I can't.
哦，我不能。
I'm on my lunch break.
我正在午休。
I would be a terrible office worker.
我会成为一个糟糕的上班族。
I would be an awful co-worker.
我会是一个糟糕的同事。
I think typically after my lunch break I have a few meetings.
我认为通常在午休后我会开几次会。
Typically after my lunch break I have a few meetings.
通常在午休后我会开几次会。
OK.
好的。
That means it doesn't happen every time but most of the time it does.
这意味着它不会每次都发生，但大多数时候都会发生。
In fact you can say most of the time can say most of the time.
事实上你可以说大部分时间可以说大部分时间。
Some things are not really strict in time maybe your lunch break is always at twelve from twelve to
有些事情在时间上并不是很严格，也许你的午休时间总是从十二点到十二点
one twelve to one but often when we get off of work or get out of school we can use around to say that
十二比一，但通常当我们下班或放学时，我们可以用周围说
it happens near that time.
它发生在那个时间附近。
So maybe you have to do some extra work after school every day and you don't leave school until around
所以也许你每天放学后都要做一些额外的工作，直到大约
four thirty pm so OK.
下午四点三十，还可以。
You can say that most of the time I get out of school around around four thirty.
你可以说大部分时间我在四点三十左右放学。
And of course that for 30 means p.m. We don't have to say p.m. because nobody gets out of school at
当然，30 点意味着下午。我们不必说下午。因为没有人在
430 am.
上午 430 点。
That is crazy.
这很疯狂。
Get off work ok.
下班就好了。
Get off work.
下班。
I could say by around by around 5:00 I'm usually ready to go home or by around 5:00 I'm usually done
我可以说大约在 5:00 左右我通常准备回家或在 5:00 左右我通常完成
with my work or by around 5:00.
我的工作或 5:00 左右。
I usually leave the office by around 5:00.
我通常在 5:00 左右离开办公室。
I usually by around 5:00 I usually leave the office or again get off work Get off of work.
我通常在 5:00 左右离开办公室或再次下班下班。
This is a way to say something happens near a time but it's not fixed.
这是一种说某事在某个时间附近发生但不是固定的方式。
If something is very fixed well then you should just use at I have lunch at 12:00 or I have lunch from
如果有什么东西固定得很好，那么你应该只使用我在 12:00 吃午饭，或者我在 12:00 吃午饭
12:00 to one or if you're a student you could say I get out of school at three thirty.
12:00 到 1 点，或者如果你是学生，你可以说我三点三十分放学。
That means it's the same every single day and it happens exactly at three thirty.
这意味着每一天都是一样的，而且恰好发生在三点三十分。
Exactly then.
正是那时。
OK.
好的。
There's no flexibility around is near about is near by around is also ok I usually get off around three
周围没有灵活性 附近 附近 附近 还可以 我通常三点左右下车
thirty.
三十。
I usually leave by around three thirty.
我通常在三点三十分左右离开。
That means before three thirty and up to three thirty or if it's specific use at or if it happens between
这意味着在三点三十分之前到三点三十分之前，或者如果它是特定用途的，或者它发生在
this time and this time we can say from two from twelve to one.
这一次，这一次，我们可以说从十二到一的二。